[music]
[Instructor] Now the Player
can pick up this Powerup,
and then it'll open up the Powerup
Indicator that will show
when we have our Powerup
so we can blast our opponents
away off of the environment.
It's still a little bit too easy,
so we're going to introduce
a bit more challenge into the game
by spawning multiple enemies
all over the screen over time.
In our SpawnManager class,
we have exactly everything
that we need to be able to spawn
multiple enemies over time.
And in order to do that, we're going
to use something called a "for() loop."
Now, a "for() loop"
is similar
to an "if() statement,"
where with an if() statement,
we used a condition
to be able to see if something was true.
For example, with something in our game,
if the Player picks up a Powerup.
A for() loop will enable
us to control the iterations
that something goes through.
So if we want something
to execute 5 times, we can do that.
For example, if we want
to have our Instantiate() method
happen 5 times,
we can use a for() loop.
So, in our Start() method,
if we type in the keyword "for,"
the way a for() loop works
is that we actually need
3 different Parameters
to be able to use this loop.
First, we need to tell
the for() loop where to start.
So we're going to create
a variable in here
for our start point, and we'll just
call it "i,"
and we'll set it to 0.
Now we need to tell the for() loop
the condition of when it should stop.
As long as "i < 3,"
then it should continue.
Once i is not less than 3,
this will make our for() loop
stop running,
since the condition
won't be true anymore.
And then we need
to tell the for() loop
how we're going get
i from 0 to 3.
So we can say "i
= i
+ 1."
Another way that we can
do this is similar
to how we multiply values by itself.
We can just say "i += 1."
But if we actually want
an even shorter way
of saying i += 1
we can actually just say "i++"
and C# will know that this
should just
add 1 to i
every time the for() loop goes through.
So what'll happen is
i will be set to 0,
it'll make an enemy,
and it'll add 1 to i,
so that i is equal to 1.
Then it'll make another enemy,
same thing, i becomes 2.
And then it'll make
another enemy,
adds 1 to i.
And then it'll stop making enemies.
And then we just need to wrap
this entire thing
in its own block,
using our curly braces.
So now this'll create 3 enemies.
Now when we press Play,
you should see
that we have 3 enemies spawn,
because they were all
created using our for() loop.
Now just to help us a little bit,
and clean up our code,
we're going to create
a new method
down at the bottom.
So we'll call this "void...
SpawnEnemyWave()"
so that this way
we can spawn our enemies.
And then we can take our code here,
put it in SpawnEnemyWave(),
and then just call "SpawnEnemyWave();."
So, what you're going to do,
is you're going to create a new method
called void SpawnEnemyWave().
In your method,
you're going to use a for() loop.
You're going to use the variable i,
set it to 0.
When i < 3,
then this for() loop will stop.
Increment i + 1 every time,
and then just call
the Instantiate() method
for our enemyPrefab.
And then call SpawnEnemyWave()
in your Start() method.
Now it's your turn.
[music]